<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<dt-button library="ColumnControl">
	<name>searchNumber</name>
	<summary>Numeric search for number based columns.</summary>
	<since>1.0.0</since>

	<description>
		This content type adds numeric search to a ColumnControl content list through a `-tag input` element, which accepts number input. The list of logic options for how the search should perform its tests are also suitable for number-based data.

		The `-tag input` element has the following attributes set in order to help present input options for numeric input (particularly on mobile devices):

		* `inputmode="numeric"`
		* `pattern="[0-9]*"`

		It should be noted that `-content search` should generally be used rather than this one directly, as `-content search` will select the most appropriate search input based on the column type.

		### Display

		It is expected that this content type will have a full cell to draw in if used at the top level, as it benefits from having a large amount of space available (i.e. other buttons won't be used along with it at the top level for a specific set of cells).

		In a dropdown, this content type will display as part of the regular content list.
	</description>

	<option type="boolean" name="clear" default="true">
		Indicate if a clear icon should be shown at the end of the search `-tag input` element. When enabled a cross icon will be shown when the input has a value and clicking on the icon will clear the search.
	</option>

	<option type="string" name="placeholder" default="">
		Value to set the `placeholder` attribute of the `-tag input` element to. The given string will have the substring `[title]` will be replaced with the column title.
	</option>

	<option type="string" name="title" default="">
		Text shown above the input, which can be used to tell the end user information about what the search will do. The given string will have the substring `[title]` will be replaced with the column title.
	</option>

	<option type="string" name="titleAttr" default="">
		Value to set the `title` attribute of the search `-tag input` element which can be used to help with accessability. The given string will have the substring `[title]` will be replaced with the column title.
	</option>

	<option type="array" name="excludeLogic" default="[]" since="1.2">
		A list of logic types which are to be removed from the list of logic types the end user can select from.
	</option>

	<example title="Manual application of search types (use `-content search` to simplify!)"><![CDATA[
new DataTable('#example', {
    columnControl: [
        {
            target: 0,
            content: ['orderStatus']
        },
        {
            target: 1,
            content: ['searchText']
        }
    ],
    columnDefs: [
        {
            targets: [3, 5],
            columnControl: {
                target: 1,
                content: ['searchNumber']
            }
        },
        {
            targets: [4],
            columnControl: {
                target: 1,
                content: ['searchDateTime']
            }
        }
    ],
    ordering: {
        indicators: false
    }
});
]]></example>
</dt-button>
