<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<dt-button library="ColumnControl">
	<name>searchDateTime</name>
	<summary>Search for date based columns.</summary>
	<since>1.0.0</since>

	<description>
		This content type adds a search input suitable for use with date-based columns. An `-tag input` element is added to the ColumnControl content list, and the list of logic options for how the search should perform its tests are also suitable for date-based data.

		If the [DataTables DateTime picker library](https://datatables.net/extensions/datetime/) is available on your page, focusing on the `-tag input` will cause a date picker to appear.

		The format of the date input will match the format used in the column if [using the builder in `datetime` rendering function](https://datatables.net/manual/data/renderers#Date-and-time-helpers).

		It should be noted that `-content search` should generally be used rather than this one directly, as `-content search` will select the most appropriate search input based on the column type.

		Examples showing the use of this content type [are available on the DataTables website](https://datatables.net/extensions/columncontrol/examples/searchDates/).

		### Display

		It is expected that this content type will have a full cell to draw in if used at the top level, as it benefits from having a large amount of space available (i.e. other buttons won't be used along with it at the top level for a specific set of cells).

		In a dropdown, this content type will display as part of the regular content list.
	</description>

	<option type="boolean" name="clear" default="true">
		Indicate if a clear icon should be shown at the end of the search `-tag input` element. When enabled a cross icon will be shown when the input has a value and clicking on the icon will clear the search.
	</option>

    <option type="string" name="format" default="" since="1.1.0">
        This option gives the ability to use a different format for the search input, than that used in the DataTable for the column in question. ColumnControl will attempt to use the same format as the DataTable column automatically, but you may wish to override this, particularly if using the `mask` option.
    </option>

    <option type="string" name="mask" default="" since="1.1.0">
        Date filtering mask. This option is used to remove components from the date / time data used for filtering and is applied to both the search input and the data in the table. A "component" in this sense is the year, month, day, hours, minutes or seconds.

        This can be useful for cases where you might wish to offer the user the ability to search a date / time value by just the date part, simplifying the search, as for a full date / time exact matching would require second precision.
        
        The format for this value is "YYYY-MM-DD[T ]hh:mm:ss.sss". Remove a component to remove it from the comparison (that unit will be set to 0). E.g. `format: 'YYYY-MM-DD'` will search only on the date part.

        The format of this field does not change based on the `format` parameter, it is always in the format described above, but you will likely wish to set `format` if you also use this one.
    </option>

	<option type="string" name="placeholder" default="">
		Value to set the `placeholder` attribute of the `-tag input` element to. The given string will have the substring `[title]` will be replaced with the column title.
	</option>

	<option type="string" name="title" default="">
		Text shown above the input, which can be used to tell the end user information about what the search will do. The given string will have the substring `[title]` will be replaced with the column title.
	</option>

	<option type="string" name="titleAttr" default="">
		Value to set the `title` attribute of the search `-tag input` element which can be used to help with accessability. The given string will have the substring `[title]` will be replaced with the column title.
	</option>

	<option type="array" name="excludeLogic" default="[]" since="1.2">
		A list of logic types which are to be removed from the list of logic types the end user can select from. Values can be:

		* `-string equal`
		* `-string notEqual`
		* `-string greater`
		* `-string less`
		* `-string empty`
		* `-string notEmpty
	</option>

	<example title="Manual application of search types (use `-content search` to simplify!)"><![CDATA[
new DataTable('#example', {
    columnControl: [
        {
            target: 0,
            content: ['orderStatus']
        },
        {
            target: 1,
            content: ['searchText']
        }
    ],
    columnDefs: [
        {
            targets: [3, 5],
            columnControl: {
                target: 1,
                content: ['searchNumber']
            }
        },
        {
            targets: [4],
            columnControl: {
                target: 1,
                content: ['searchDateTime']
            }
        }
    ],
    ordering: {
        indicators: false
    }
});
]]></example>
</dt-button>
